# ĐOÀN VĂN SƠN

# React Developer

0347200992

2001.sondv@gmail.com

#### SUMMARY

I'm a Software Engineer with over 3 years of experience in Web Development. I have more 3 years of experience in Modern Front-End Web Development and 1 year of Back-End related technologies as NodeJS and Laravel.

With my knowledge of UI/UX design, I enjoy solving front-end problems and creating the best user experience for users. I also spend time learning new technologies and best practices to become a better engineer.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages: JavaScript & TypeScript, PHP, Python.

#### Libraries/Frameworks:

- ReactJS, NextJS, NodeJS, PHP Laravel.
- Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, MaterialUI.
- Webpack/Babel, Git, Shopify App Bridge.

Database Management Systems: PostgreSQL, MongoDB, MySQL.

#### Other:

- Experience in setting up CI/CD pipelines, using Docker.
- Hands-on experience with Cloud Computing Platforms: AWS

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### **NTQ Solution - Web Developer**

05/2022 - Now

Project: Partner Portal (3 members, 1 front-end, 2 back-end)

11/2024 - Now

• Description: Partner Portal is a subsystem of Gori. It manages the entire shipping process from the origin partner outside the U.S. to the origin airport, then to the destination airport in the U.S., and finally to the destination partner in the U.S.

#### Technologies:

- Front-end: React + TypeScript + Bootstrap.
- Back-end: PHP Laravel, MySQL.

#### Responsibilities:

- Build the source code base, optimize performance and clean code.
- Mainly responsible for defining the architecture, coding conventions, and estimating task completion time.
- Design the user interface based on customer ideas and propose solutions.

Project: ShipBae (6 members, 1 front-end, 5 back-end) 06/2022 - Now

Description: ShipBae, a product of Gori Company (USA), is a logistics software
designed to streamline order creation, shipments, and claims for admins and
sales teams. It supports seamless order synchronization and management from
platforms like Shopify, TikTok, Temu, Amazon, Walmart, and ShipStation.
As the ultimate eCommerce fulfillment solution, ShipBae helps businesses save
time and costs by providing the best shipping rates, label printing, package
tracking, and efficient order management.

## · Technologies:

- Legacy front-end project: React + Metronic.
- Migrate to a new front-end project: React + TypeScript + Bootstrap.
- Back-end: PHP Laravel, PostgreSQL.

# • Responsibilities:

- Build the source code base, optimize performance and clean code for the frontend source of the project.
- Mainly responsible, Define the architecture, coding convention and estimating front-end task completion time for front-end project.
- Review Code & Support members of the team to ensure code quality.
- Handles all highly complex frontend tasks such as: subdomain, decentralization, onboarding, asidebar, create order, create shipment, create claims, settings page,...
- Ability to create Reusable Components that can be utilized throughout the Application Form Validations and Handling Dynamic Validations for Form using Yup.
- Creating Form Using Formik, Yup.
- Perform backend tasks using PHP such as payment processing (PayPal),
   barcode generation, and sending Mailchimp emails and syncs order TikTok.
- Develop Partner Portal features within the ShipBae system and establish the connection between the two systems.

**Project:** BaeWatch (3 members, 1 front-end, 2 back-end) **11/2022 - 04/2023** 

Description: BaeWatch is a subsystem of ShipBae. It is an app on the Shopify
e-commerce platform that helps sellers synchronize their orders with ShipBae
for management. Additionally, it provides features such as order management,
claims processing, and insurance settings for customers using the BaeWatch
store on Shopify.

## Technologies:

- Front-end: React + TypeScript + Shopify App Bridge + Bootstrap.
- Back-end: PHP Laravel, PostgreSQL.

### • Responsibilities:

Build the source code base, optimize performance and clean code.

 Perform tasks related to authentication and apexcharts and connection tasks between ShipBae and BaeWatch. In addition, to tasks related to settings, claims, insurance for BaeWatch application on Shopify.

# **Tigren Solution - Intern Developer**

02/2022 - 05/2022

Project: PWA Demo (4 members, 2 front-end, 2 back-end)

- **Description:** PWA Demo is provides full Magento core features & different interfaces for desktop & mobile.
- Technologies:
  - Front-end: React + TypeScript + Tailwind CSS + GraphQL.
  - Back-end: PHP Magento.
- Responsibilities:
  - Study source code and Do extensions such as: realated, up shell, cross shell...
  - Custom PWA theme: home page, details page,...

#### ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

There are also a number of personal and freelance projects.

Personal project 07/2021 - now

- Schat E2EE: Schat E2EE is my graduation project a web app for messaging, media sharing, and voice/video calls with end-to-end encryption (E2EE). It uses NextJS, Tailwind CSS for the front-end and NodeJS (Express), PostgreSQL, AWS for the back-end. I developed both front-end and back-end, implemented realtime messaging, voice/video calls, and E2EE, and deployed the system on AWS.
- **Box Studio**: Box Studio is a landing page providing services in marketing, media, & multi-platform digital content. It is written in React.js and Bootstrap.
- Booking Care: Booking Care is a system that helps patients schedule medical appointments. Additionally, it includes an admin page to assist in managing doctors, hospital rooms, and doctor schedules. It is written in ReactJS and NodeJS Express.

#### **EDUCATION & HONORS**

Best Performer of the Division Award 2024 (NTQ Solution)

Academy of Cryptography Techniques (KMA)
 Information Security: 3.0/4.0

• School scholarship for Semester 2 of the academic year 2021-2022 **12/2022** 

School scholarship for Semester 1 of the academic year 2021-2022
 06/2022

School scholarship for Semester 2 of the academic year 2020-2021
 12/2021

• Encouragement prize for the Hackathon competition at the club level **01/2020**